Guide to the Archons of Colophon Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Archons of Colophon Records
1915-1990.
Archons of Colophon.
5.4 linear ft (ca. 5,500 items in 13 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078665
History
Originally founded in 1909, the Archons of Colophon is an association of American library administrators.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, minutes, and financial records, 1915, 1928-1974, 1983, in the organization's archives, including announcements of meetings, letters of acceptance and regret, membership lists, financial records, some miscellaneous notes concerning members, and material relating to the history of the Archons.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two sections; records received in 1990 were placed at the end of the collection.
Subjects
Library science--Societies, etc.; Library administrators--Societies, etc.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1958 M58 Archons of Colophon Gift
Correspondence, minutes, agendas, membership and financial files, 1960-1989. Archons of Colophon Gift
Gift of Archons of Colophon, 1958-1974; 1983; 1990.
Finding aid in repository; folder level control.
- Records
  - 1915, 1928-1943 (Box 1)
  - 1944-1947 (Box 2)
  - 1948-1950 (Box 3)
  - 1951-1955 (Box 4)
  - 1955-1972
    - A-History (Part I) (Box 5)
      (One 1983 letter has been added to the file "General Correspondence Folder")
    - History (Part II)-Meetings (1970) (Box 6)
    - Meetings (1970-1971)-Portraits (End of file) (Box 7)
      (Includes meeting minutes through 1974)
  - Ash, Lee. The Archons of Colophon 1909-1917 and 1926-1969: Much and Little Changed, 1969 (Box 8)
    (Multiple copies of a printed history of Archons)
- 1990 Addition
  - 1960-1979 (Box 9)
  - 1980-1987 (Box 10)
  - 1987-1989 (Box 11)
  - Minutes, 1954-1985 (Box 11)
    (Please note that there is a set of minutes interfiled in the Convener’s files, 1970-1979)
  - Membership Files, 1980-1988 (Box 12)
  - Financial Records, 1975-1989 (Box 13)
- 2012 Accession
  - Ballots, 2005-2009, (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - Invoices, 2005-2010 (Box 14)
  - Membership, 2005-2010 (Box 14)
  - Bank Statements, 2005-2009, (2 folders) (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2010 (Box 14)
  - Permanenet Records (Box 14)
  - Floppy Disks (Box 14)
  - Committee on Archives and History (Box 15)
  - History (Box 15)
  - Nominating Committee (Box 15)
  - Secretary and Treasurer Files (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Eligibility and Membership (Box 15)
  - Eligibility and Membership (Box 15)
  - Membership Lists (Box 15)
  - Eligibility and Membership, (2 folders) (Box 15)
  - Agendas (Box 15)
  - Committees (Box 15)
  - Convenor, 1989-1990 (Box 15)
  - Convenor Guide, 1986-1997 (Box 15)
  - Dues Notices (Box 15)
  - General Files, 2003-2005 (Box 15)